Ovidiu Bahnean

Chicago, IL

Phone: +1 (630) 777 0669 | Email: <u>obahnean@gmail.com</u>

Passionate Software Developer with more than 3 years of professional experience building web applications. Proficient in the full-stack development, particularly in a Java World. Successfully worked with service-oriented architectures (SOA) and web services. Holds a BS in Computer Science.

#Skills

Front-End	Back End	Source Control	Frameworks	UI/UX
JavaScript ES6 / jQuery	REST / SOAP	Git (Git Flow) / FTP	Spring / SpringBoot	Wireframing / UML
CSS / SASS / LESS	SQL / PL-SQL	SCRUM / Agile	Hibernate	Prototyping
HTML / XHTML / JSP	AWS	GitHub	Angular	Adobe Suite
Gulp / Webpack	Apache	Jira / Bitbucket	Bootstrap	User Stories
508 Accessibility	Java	Jenkins	NodeJS	Atomic Design

#Professional Experience

CompuSystems / Web Developer

December 2019 - July 2022: Lisle, IL | Full-Time

- Ly Implemented new UI and templating system with Bootstrap and JavaScript to improve UX and system flexibility.
- Ly Employed web services to import client membership information into custom web application.
- L Built and especially consumed Java based APIs to facilitate Single-Sign-On or Membership type of functionality.
- L, Coordinated closely with UI/UX, Design, and QA. Prototyped and Wireframed.
- Ly Teamed up with the Analytics Team and collected data for their models.
- Ly Incorporated payment processing systems like PayPal for faster checkouts.
- Ly Government contract work adhering to Section 508 and WCAG2 Level for AA accessibility.

Revature / Full Stack Developer

May 2019 - October 2019: Tampa, FL | Contract

- Ly Interfaced with and developed some large-scale internal applications.
- L API-based backends written in Java with Spring and Hibernate.
- L, Reviewed fundamental concepts and methodologies in JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3.
- L Customed CSS/SCSS styling written with BEM-IT naming conventions.
- L Executed Angular front-end framework with Gulp, Webpack, and NodeJS.
- L, Pipelined with Jenkins and AWS EC2 for CI/CD.

#Education

University of Illinois at Chicago / Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

August 2014 - May 2018: Chicago IL